[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever run through a stop signal at second?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not seeing it or just thinking you could get it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't run with your head down.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't see it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't see the coach give me a stop sign the whole way.
[SPEAKER_02]: When you run with your head down you can't see.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a pretty good question for him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well I thought I could make that for him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a better chance on third base and I had one second to score.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where you gonna score from now?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said going back to Vince.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you out at any times you ran through the stop sign?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Does it ever get you out at third when he's tripled?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he got me out then when I ran through the stop line.
[SPEAKER_01]: Going home, you mean?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I mean on plays where you didn't make a triple but you tried to and were thrown out at third.
[SPEAKER_02]: Happened a few times, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to talk about this 33 ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, go ahead.
[SPEAKER_01]: We started out the spring training with a Mohawk club, looked like a major league Mohawk club on paper.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, I played right field and they had Terry Moore in center.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Jack Rothrock played left field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Rothrock.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, first base he had Mickey Heath, second base was Burgess Friday.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill and Myers played short.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lou Riggs played third base.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a big, big team, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: New Lansky and O'Day were the kickers.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Paul Lee, Bill Lee, Jim Winford, Lefty Heisey.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jim who?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jim Winford.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good kickers, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we went on, we won the Pennant by 12 or 15 ballgames.
[SPEAKER_01]: So eight boys off of the 33 ballclub were playing on a 34 ballclub with the Cardinals in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they beat Detroit in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dizzy won two games and Paul won the other two and lost one.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that was the ballclub we were in.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who were the eight?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Who were the what?
[SPEAKER_02]: The eight players.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Galancy was one, Whitehead, Riggs, Rothrock, Terry Moore, Paul Dean, and Bill Weed.
[SPEAKER_02]: And O'Day maybe too?
[SPEAKER_01]: O'Day, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's remarkable.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a good book, that.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you do in the Junior World Series?
[SPEAKER_02]: We won one of the World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: What'd you play?
[SPEAKER_02]: Played Syracuse.
[SPEAKER_02]: Four straight?
[SPEAKER_02]: Where did you live in Columbus at that time?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you move here permanently then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Where did you spend the winter months in these years?
[SPEAKER_02]: Right here in Columbus.
[SPEAKER_02]: Say back in the 1920s.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, 1920s in South Dakota.
[SPEAKER_01]: I lived in Madison, South Dakota.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you made that your home?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I lived there ten years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you get married then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you marry a gal from up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: I did, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Your family started up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Absolutely, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Your children were born up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, you lived in Madison until about 1930?
[SPEAKER_02]: And then where'd you move to?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, from there I went to...
[SPEAKER_01]: I lived in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a sister there.
[SPEAKER_02]: At your home, your parents home?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I lived with her.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then what?
[SPEAKER_01]: Then she died.
[SPEAKER_01]: I lived in Omaha.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I lived in Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_01]: I lived in Cincinnati one year when I played over there and I came back to Columbus.
[SPEAKER_02]: You really moved around and lived where you played and didn't have a home that you went back to?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I always lived where I played.
[SPEAKER_00]: You lived in Columbus a long time?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I came to Columbus in 32 and I stayed in Columbus until 42.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where did you live here in Columbus?
[SPEAKER_01]: 3776 South 9th Street.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is it a home?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, I own a place down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You own a home?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that was convenient.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: What'd you do in the winters?
[SPEAKER_02]: Hunt and fish.
[SPEAKER_01]: Around here or did you go up north?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I went just around here at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I had a job.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a job as a sailor.
[SPEAKER_01]: I followed the ball players, I sold beer, but I didn't like that job too well.
[SPEAKER_01]: I sold a lot of... How did you get that job?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I went up the bowling alley one day, to bowl, and there was a man up there by the name of Frank Nagle, and Jeff Hart Yeager, I think was his first name, owned the Yeager Machine Company, and they had a distributor for beer.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, Nate asked me if I wanted to work, and I said, yeah, I wanted to work with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Went out in the country and took a load of beer on a truck.
[SPEAKER_01]: Went out and sold it all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Come back, I sold lots of beer for him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you do this a number of years?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, just that one year was all.
[SPEAKER_01]: When would that have been?
[SPEAKER_01]: That was in 1933.
[SPEAKER_01]: After the 33 season?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't like South beer?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I didn't like it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't like the idea of hanging around those beer guys too much.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, you go in and some guy says, here, buy a beer, drink one.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I drank it all, I'd probably weigh 800 pounds.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, did you have any other jobs in off-seasons after that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I worked at the A-Machine, I mean, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I worked over at, uh... Jeffery's Machine Company.
[SPEAKER_01]: I worked up there for about...
[SPEAKER_01]: Which is this?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jeffery's Manufacturing Company, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's in Columbus?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was, uh, running a... Jeffery's.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jeffery's.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jeffery's Manufacturing Company.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was running a beer cart making these sprockets for the general U.S. tank.
[SPEAKER_01]: I worked there for what one winter we called.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was in about 37 I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, 36.
[SPEAKER_02]: You just liked hunting fish too much, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: You liked hunting fish too much, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did your wife and family go with you on your trips during the season?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: They always had it arranged where if you could talk Ricky out of it, the money's transportation for your family.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was a little rough to deal with, I mean.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you, did all the Cardinal Minor League players sign with Ricky, deal with him directly?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, they signed him, but if you wouldn't sign, why, they'd get ahold of business manager and call Ricky up, see him, speak to him in the town and want to know why you wouldn't sign him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Give you a lecture.
[SPEAKER_01]: Give you a lecture about this and that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pretty smart baseball man, as he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He knows the game's made of these, but nobody's monkey.
[SPEAKER_02]: I talked to somebody, though, who played under him, said he wasn't a very good manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know about his manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: He talked to pretty good folks.
[SPEAKER_02]: Forgotten, but somebody did play under him for a year or two.
[SPEAKER_01]: As a business manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember one time we had a meeting here in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when we had a good ball problem.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, when I played with the Redbirds, they were all good ballers.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, he told me one day, he said, if I had nine ball players like Nick Cullip, he said, I wouldn't worry about nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, that's all I'd want.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, at the end of the season, he sent all these ball players to the big leagues, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: But he left the old Cullip right here in Columbus.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I said, well, I said, this spring I'm going to find out something.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I held out for more money.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was already into Avon Park in the spring training.
[SPEAKER_01]: So Ricky come to town, and I was back in the field plowing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Come down with that guy driving his car, you know, that red automobile, dust flying.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I said, well, here he come.
[SPEAKER_01]: He come down and said, what are you doing?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm like, what do you think I'm doing?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm flying a kite.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got kind of smart with him, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't want to give me any money.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he said, when are you going to spring training?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, when you give me some money.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, well, I can't give you any more money.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, well, I'll tell you something, Mr. Rickey.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the statement you made, he said, if you had nine ball players like Nick Colton, you wouldn't worry about nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, do this priest.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, nah, you certainly did.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, how much money you want?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I told him.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we went right in the house, called up Al Bannister, signed Colton, get him on the plane right away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I got a kick out of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never swore he was a writer, did he?
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd forgotten he said that, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's interesting.
[SPEAKER_02]: Al Bannister, who was he?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was the general manager of all the programs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he the general manager all these years in the 30s?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: They took him to St. Louis and made him
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the supervisor of all the ballparks, you know, on equipment and things like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But since then he has passed away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who took over from him here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Red Trotman.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Billy Southwest stay as manager all the years you were here?
[SPEAKER_01]: He has a farm up here at Sunbury.
[SPEAKER_01]: He died not too long ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's been several years, I think, since he died.
[SPEAKER_02]: Years, I would say.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he manager all the time you were here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who, Southwest?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I first came here, Ray Blade was the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I came back again, and Bert Shatner was the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then Dyer was the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Southwest, he was the, uh, Harry Leibold.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nemo?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Harry Leibold.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nemo Leibold?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Nemo we called him, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you live in Columbus?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I grew up in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was never down here very much, but I followed the baseball history very closely.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you're in Sacramento now.
[SPEAKER_01]: What happened there?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1936, they were going to put a
[SPEAKER_01]: a good ball club in Sacramento.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what Ricky said.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, Nick, I want you to go to Sacramento.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I said, well, I said, if I have to play triple-A ball, why can't you make a deal or give my release so I can play here with some other club in the American Association?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wouldn't do that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, well, I said, it's going to cost me money to go to Sacramento.
[SPEAKER_01]: So finally, we got together.
[SPEAKER_01]: He paid my transportation out there for the family and everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went to Sacramento.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a pretty good fall.
[SPEAKER_01]: We finished first in one attendance in Sacramento.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was the same year that Enos Slaughter came here to Columbus.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we've done all right out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your manager in Sacramento?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Tillerson.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've played for a lot of people, haven't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was there both years I was at Sacramento.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a good year at 37.
[SPEAKER_02]: What happened at 38?
[SPEAKER_02]: Fell down a little bit there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was beginning to slip a little bit, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you're getting along now in years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they play those long schedules in the Coastal League then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: 180 games?
[SPEAKER_02]: 175 or 80 games, I can't remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was your favorite ballpark out on the West Coast?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have one?
[SPEAKER_02]: Los Angeles.
[SPEAKER_01]: The old Wrigley Field?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Wrigley Field.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a good ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a good ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were all good ballparks outside of Oakland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oakland had a terrible ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it had all that crap and grass, a bunch of grass, you know?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it would bounce one way and bounce the other way.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't keep it up very long, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had two clubs played over in Frisco.
[SPEAKER_01]: The San Francisco Mission and the San Francisco Shield.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they use the same park?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they used the same park.
[SPEAKER_01]: The same thing down at Los Angeles.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hollywood played in the Los Angeles park.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did, where you have two teams in one town like that, and then you had Oakland too, really three teams there, what kind of support did they get?
[SPEAKER_02]: How could fans develop loyalties for one or the other?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they, do you know?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how they did it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they both draw pretty well?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they drew very well, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a lot of rivalry now, like if you say Los Angeles is playing for Hollywood, the fans from Hollywood and the fans from Los Angeles all go out and vote for our team.
[SPEAKER_01]: They've got, you know, a group for one that was from L.A. that we couldn't win.
[SPEAKER_02]: Would one of the teams be the home team one time and the other team would be the home team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's all the same.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was in Sacramento's ballpark.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did they call it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I bet you would like to play in Sacramento this year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have you heard about it?
[SPEAKER_02]: They brought a club back in.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess they haven't had a team for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: They have a 233-foot left-field fence.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, you hit one of your fists out of there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Left-fielders can throw runners out at first base.
[SPEAKER_02]: Something went wrong.
[SPEAKER_02]: They planned to have the park redesigned, but the city didn't come through, so they had to play it loose.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sacramento's in last place, and they've got 270 home runs, something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think how many of you that got hit out there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Might have hit quite a few of them too.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd have to put an asterisk or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, did you like it out there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you keep your home here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't sell your property in Columbus when you went out to Sacramento?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't?
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: I lived on South High Street.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you sell your property here?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I kept it all.
[SPEAKER_02]: You plan to make this your home then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Houston?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, 1939, Ricky sent me to Houston.
[SPEAKER_01]: Eddie Dyer was the man of the ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's before he went to the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went down there and I had a good year down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a fine year.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was over in a lot of runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did 25.
[SPEAKER_01]: 30 home runs, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: 29 years old, too, or 38.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, uh, they had a, a night for Dyer down there, and they gave him an automobile.
[SPEAKER_01]: We all walked up to the plate, like everybody else did, and the band would start honking, and say, give the automobile a color.
[SPEAKER_01]: See?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, boy, it'll be all right, see, and it kind of got under his hide a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, about
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, this is the only town that minor in baseball where they give two automobiles away at one time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they turn around about a week before the season and they give you a new Chevrolet.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I was very proud of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: At the 39 and 40, I... Wasn't it hot down there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was it in the hot summer afternoon playing ball in Houston?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a hot summer afternoon in Sacramento all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I played out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I made it so bad we played all night games.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then on a Sunday, we played day games at Doubleheader.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd walk right out of the motel that night, out of the hotel.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, this knocked your tail off.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you play night games in the week at Houston too?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then the Sunday games there?
[SPEAKER_02]: I've heard Houston's probably the hottest place to play ball in the country.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it's hot down there.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why they need the Astrodome.
[SPEAKER_02]: And, uh, well, what about the 1940, after the 40's season?
[SPEAKER_01]: After the 40's season?
[SPEAKER_01]: You played with Houston in 40, then near Asheville in 41.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was at Asheville as a manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, this is your first job as manager?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's my first job.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you get that job?
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: First week?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a cardinal club.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he sent me down there to Asheville.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob Rice was the gentleman who was the traveling secretary for Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we went down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were scrambling in and out of first place all summer long.
[SPEAKER_01]: Before I went down there, I picked up a boy right here in town.
[SPEAKER_01]: His name was Bill Shuey.
[SPEAKER_01]: S-H-U-E-Y.
[SPEAKER_01]: A good ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had a big, long, tall kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: Left hand hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took him down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He stole 45 bases out of 48 attempts.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I had another kid by the name of Polly that the Cardinals sent out.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess we had about a month to go and he said,
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, yeah, I know well, I know what you're going to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're going to take Shoei and Polly and send them to Peppermore at the Sacramento.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, how'd you know?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, that's what you come down here for.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, Pepper's scrambling out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's got a 10-game lead.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's probably going to holler at some more ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's what happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he took the two best ballplayers I had and sent them out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he sent me some kid by the name of Ken Johnson.
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Left-hand pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: This kid come down here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't even know how to put a uniform on.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was so hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was wild.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I couldn't fix him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I put him in losing ball games and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that was in 41.
[SPEAKER_01]: So in 42, they sent me to Pocatello for the reason Bill and Lancey was catching at
[SPEAKER_01]: Pocatello and they thought they'd sent him to Oxford with a climatic condition, it would help him, he had TB.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we switched to, we won the penalty in Pocatello, Idaho.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then that was in 43,
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Came back to Columbus now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I was a manager in Columbus on 43.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Ricky do that too?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Ricky do that also?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he appoint you here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Ricky?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I came back in 43.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, 41 and 42, Bert Shotton and Dyer were here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they finished in second place.
[SPEAKER_01]: And won the World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I came here then in 43.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we finished 4th, no we finished 2nd and won the playoff and beat the Therapeutics in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: So in 44, we come back and we lost, we didn't get in the playoff, we lost out by half the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kansas City beat the Cowboys, so we didn't get in.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, I was one of the trouble beginners.
[SPEAKER_01]: I asked Sam Braden for a raise.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that after the 44 season?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it was after the 44 season.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're off this sheet now, so...
[SPEAKER_01]: So he said, uh... Well, he said, by you coming down to St. Louis to ask for a raise, he said, we don't think you're an organization man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I've been in the organization 12 years and not an organization man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, give me my release.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he got hot about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He got hotter thinking about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Sam Breeden.
[SPEAKER_01]: Breeden, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you know...
[SPEAKER_01]: If you're, uh...
[SPEAKER_01]: in line to manage the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, sure am.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, if Southwest wasn't in the World Series, how more am I going to manage that?
[SPEAKER_01]: So they finally did give him my release, and so I went over to Milwaukee and managed over there five years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think he meant it when he said you were in line to manage the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what's he going to do with Southwest?
[SPEAKER_01]: He just got through winning the World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did he mean, I wonder?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what he meant.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't figure that out.
[SPEAKER_02]: What do you mean when you said you weren't an organization man?
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I come down and ask for a raise.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, look, I said, the other two managers you had, I'd done just as good a job as they did.
[SPEAKER_01]: I finished right where they did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wasn't a playoff.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they go to the big league and you get a big raise.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dyer and Stratton made good money over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a fine manager, by the way, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: That fixed me with the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did it upset you to leave the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did it upset you very much to leave the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see where there was no advantage for me to go any higher, you know, with the way they were doing the run across ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I can't blame them for that because it's pretty hard to fire a manager if he went to the Panthers and the World Series and everything, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you happen to go to Milwaukee?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well,
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Veck one day, he said, I was at home, and he called up and he said, can I talk to you?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, where are you at?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, Phoenix, Arizona.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, how about your manager at Milwaukee Ball Club?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, come on over.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went over there, and when I managed the Redbirds here, I would have made $8,000.
[SPEAKER_01]: But when I went to Milwaukee, he said, all right, here's your contract, and I worked there, I made $12,000.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the biggest contract I ever had.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I stayed over there five years.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would be 45 through 49?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we won the pennant in 45.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the playoff, we got beat in the playoff.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next year we won the playoff and I was voted the Minor League Man of the Year.
[SPEAKER_01]: 46?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So after that, then Perini, the Braves moved in, the Boston Braves, they bought the franchise.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they sent us some pretty good ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had Alan Dark and Danny Mertzau.
[SPEAKER_01]: between the double play combination.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did anybody own Milwaukee before then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was this just Vecco unto himself?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did the Major League have a connection with Milwaukee?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the Braves bought it as a farm team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: In about 50 was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, the Braves come in there and
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, 45 he came.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they stayed there three years.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then they decided that they were going to change.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they sent Jake Flowers in there, the general manager, and he was one of those general managers who wanted to run the whole outfit.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, he'd bring the lineup down to you and everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Jake Flowers?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I told Jake Flowers, I said, look at here, I sit down.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I can't make a line up for my ball club, you're so big and I'm so small, you can have your ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I resigned.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was the end of the season then.
[SPEAKER_01]: So in the meantime, Jack Dunn called me up for Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he said, what are you doing?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm not doing anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Come on over to Baltimore, Jack Dundee.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, I flew over there and signed a contract with Baltimore and we finished third and beat Walter Olson from Montreal in the playoff.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is in 50?
[SPEAKER_02]: Just 1950?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And in 51 I was still at Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: We finished 4th or 5th I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, 6th I think we finished.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, then they decided they were going to make a change, and they got a working agreement with Philadelphia, and Philadelphia wanted to pick their own manager, you see.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's the way it turned out.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was out with John.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was 50 and 51 you were with Baltimore, and not in 52.
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, in 53 the St. Louis Browns went to Baltimore, so.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we took your places out of the job, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: So what'd you do after, what'd you do, nothing in 52, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I was in baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was at Albuquerque.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Worked for the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you get that job?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I seen a piece of paper where there was a manual, so I put it in, I applied for the job, and I got it right away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it Wrigley you wrote to him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is it right to Wrigley?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went out there and we finished fourth, and I didn't like it out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't like the climatic conditions.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I resigned out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I went to Fargo, North Dakota, and I managed up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was my last year.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1953?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Weren't you with Columbus after that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: I come back to manage the jets two years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I thought so.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was after the jets got here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then you went to Pennsylvania and Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_02]: Went to Lancaster, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you were here with Columbus in 54, 55?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I was here two years.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was just right after the Cardinal was pulled out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's when Kansas City pulled in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kansas City, they had a working agreement with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was here those two years, and then Pittsburgh moved in.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they sent Shepard over there, the man with the Pittsburgh motorboat.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you were at Lancaster?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: How long were you there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Two years.
[SPEAKER_02]: As an Eastern, or?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_02]: What league was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: International Western Bound.
[SPEAKER_02]: Interstate, or?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, the Eastern League.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was your greatest thrill in baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had quite a few of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess hitting home runs in base four.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a big thrill when I hit them three triples.
[SPEAKER_01]: What year was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob, Mr. Davies sent that in.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hasn't got that in yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: At Denver, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I was playing with Omaha.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, wow, it's been 23 or 24, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I need 23 triples here someplace.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or 22.
[SPEAKER_02]: How was your throwing arm?
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a good arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you get many assists from the offense?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could throw no longer.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could throw good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Too accurate too.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean I'm not crazy for what I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a good arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the toughest pitcher to hit off of?
[SPEAKER_02]: Earnshaw.
[SPEAKER_02]: George Earnshaw.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever bat against Walter Johnson?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm glad I didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: Philadelphia had a great pitch, the staff over in Algeria had Lefty Groves over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He won, I think he won the 25, 26, Ruth Warburg, John Quinn, you remember him?
[SPEAKER_01]: George Earnshaw?
[SPEAKER_02]: I've talked to Lefty Groves.
[SPEAKER_02]: He lives up here in Norwalk, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a hard man to interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: He doesn't say much.
[SPEAKER_02]: Those great years, you know, he said, wasn't that a great thrill, having that great year he had?
[SPEAKER_02]: He just doesn't talk much.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't be any worse than I am.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're great.
[SPEAKER_02]: This is wonderful.
[SPEAKER_02]: A lot of good stories.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you think of any funny things that happen in baseball, little plays or incidents that are real,
[SPEAKER_01]: They're really humorous.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the one humorous was about Babe Herman.
[SPEAKER_01]: With that glove, that was a dandy, I thought.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anything, any others, you know, along that line that come to mind?
[SPEAKER_01]: Ah, we were playing a game down in New Orleans when I was with Atlanta, Larry Gilbert was the man.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a pitcher out there by the name of Bill Whittaker and he had a big, big fat stomach on him, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: So I hit a ball through the box and it hit him in the stomach, see, and it knocked him down and he threw me out and fell over.
[SPEAKER_01]: So everybody come running out there and they asked, Billy, you heard me?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, no, except it broke two quarts.
[SPEAKER_01]: He asked me what to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, what do you want to do?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you want to play ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm not going to tell you what to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not going to make you.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't make him do it if you don't want to.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, well, I don't want to play ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, just forget about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was his name?
[SPEAKER_02]: Henry.
[SPEAKER_02]: Henry Nick.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a junior?
[SPEAKER_02]: Why were you called Nick and not Hank?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, my second name was Iznick.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nick was his name.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there was another colop, a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was going to ask about him.
[SPEAKER_01]: A left-hander.
[SPEAKER_01]: His name was Norman.
[SPEAKER_01]: So very late, Iznick.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then they called Iznick, and we'll have my colop come along.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a young colop, that's what it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: They called Norman colop, Nick.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I hit him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was pitching for Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he came back from the old Federal League, he was about the end of his life.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, I asked Mike Kelly, he said, hey, where is this color pad?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was down at a pepper game, you know, in the bun game, right field, before the game ever started.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a hair of that, he said, a big blond-haired kid down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he comes down and he says, Nick?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, my name's Colt, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we shook hands, sat down and talked quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of his relations came from down in West Virginia someplace.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we got to talking, and he said, I'm with Pitts today.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, oh yeah?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the first time I met him, I didn't know him at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: So around the basic, he didn't say nothing as big as I looked at him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He looked pretty good to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Next time I come up, they hit another one off of me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had two home runs off of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he said, well, I'll tell him what the score is now.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, I'm your cousin because I can't get you out.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what they call a pitcher, you know, when you hit him pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Call him a cousin.
[SPEAKER_02]: What year was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Where did that happen?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was over in Louisville.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was in... Was that that...
[SPEAKER_02]: And you were with maybe Minneapolis?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: But you weren't related, though?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a rather unusual name.
[SPEAKER_01]: It is, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've looked all over.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't find any other name.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he have a very good career in the big time, you know?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who?
[SPEAKER_01]: Norman?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was a good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: He pitched with the Yankees all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Your ancestry is German then, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And your parents come from Germany?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, my parents was born right there in the Weller Spring, but my grandfather and grandmother came from over in Germany.
[SPEAKER_02]: I noticed your birth certificate there is in German.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You said German was spoken at home?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: German was spoken in your home, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we went to a church where they speak the sermon in German all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Are you Lutherans?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That name is K on the birth certificate.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's Kulop.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think the Kulop came along as they went into baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think they misunderstood.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: The guy went down to the manager one time, when I dropped the cooler and he said, give me a line up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: Went on down to the color pitch and the board writer put down C-L-L-O-P, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's where my nigga went for that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had to go get a birth certificate and have them fix it over again.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you boys wash your hands if you have to wash your hands.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'll leave it here, ma'am.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, after a very good lunch now, we'll... You're right down to business now.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got a lot of things came up while we were eating here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Delicious chicken dinner.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you're more than welcome.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm happy to do it for you.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we got Mr. Culp talking about some other things there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mentioned
[SPEAKER_02]: Fred Blake, he right away, he knew Fred Blake, he roomed with him, I guess, when, with Columbus here, was it, or when was it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I was here with Columbus.
[SPEAKER_02]: 32?
[SPEAKER_02]: 32, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's a, it says, July 8th, 1923, at Denver, three triples in one ballgame.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got this from Mr. Davies, see, that's what he put it in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I want to check on that, that's great.
[SPEAKER_02]: So what was the Fred Blake story now that bought the... Buzzard did 432 home runs and I did 417 home runs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah, this is a list of all-time minor league home run leaders which Bob Davis has prepared.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think that includes in the major leagues, does it?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, probably not.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Hauser's fourth.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And who's George Prescott?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: 399.
[SPEAKER_01]: How many?
[SPEAKER_01]: 399?
[SPEAKER_02]: Prescott is tied with Hauser.
[SPEAKER_02]: 399.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know any.
[SPEAKER_02]: Let me just read these off for the tape.
[SPEAKER_02]: Buzz Arlett, 432.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nick Culp, 417.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not counting his year of Madison in the Dakota League in 1920.
[SPEAKER_02]: We don't have any record on that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Merv Connors, 400.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Hauser, 399.
[SPEAKER_02]: George Prescott, 399.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jack Graham, 384.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ted Gullick, 370.
[SPEAKER_02]: Muscle Shoal, 362.
[SPEAKER_02]: Frank Kelleher, 358.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Gordon Nell, 358.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ray Perry, 348.
[SPEAKER_02]: Smeed Jolly, 340.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Bowman, 337.
[SPEAKER_02]: Norman Small, 336.
[SPEAKER_02]: Moose Claybaugh, 336.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dick Greco, 333.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bunny Brief, 332.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ken Gettler, 330.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ab Wright, 317.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ted Norbert, 317.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hector Espino, 314, and Ron Camacho, 310.
[SPEAKER_02]: Those last two did not include Mexican League totals of 73.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jim Poole, 310, and Jerry Witte, 308.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's 417.
[SPEAKER_02]: We were talking about this, the matter of home runs and his three triples in one game in the minors.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we got talking about Fred Blake.
[SPEAKER_02]: He remembers being a teammate with him, your roommate, and told an interesting story about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's the story, one I told you over there was they were going to let him go, you know, release him.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, he pitched a pretty good ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think his score was 7 to 4, or 7 to 3, or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, anyway, come the 19, they get two men out, and he sent me in a pinch hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I looked down there, they had a three-nothing column.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bubba Gennard was pitching for Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: I kicked the ball over the left field briefing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whole none, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And old Fred didn't take no devil out of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: What he did, he saved his job.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a winning pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: He saved his job, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a nice fellow.
[SPEAKER_01]: I liked him.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he wanted to celebrate.
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: He invited you out to the house.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, invited me out.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had some homebrew.
[SPEAKER_01]: We lived up in Orange, and I always liked that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a little black puppy up there with a copper spangle or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that dog was up on everything in that house.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jumping over the place.
[SPEAKER_01]: His wife had lots of shoes getting here out of the icebox.
[SPEAKER_01]: He opened up the bottom.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what the hell happened to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It exploded.
[SPEAKER_01]: Clear up to the ceiling.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was your, that's the rest of your home run?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said that was the rest of your... Yeah, he said, here's the rest of your home run.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, Tornado.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a good sinker.
[SPEAKER_01]: He pitched him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I heard that ball come in and hit you on the pitch and knock the bat out of your hand.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had kind of a short career, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he hurt himself somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hurt his back or I don't know which way it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was very high.
[SPEAKER_01]: He caught up in the cover on the lake.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, he was up there when they got Hack Wilson involved.
[SPEAKER_01]: Old son of a boy, Hack.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you know Hack Wilson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Rick Steveson.
[SPEAKER_01]: Woody English.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, uh, what was his third baseman, second baseman's name?
[SPEAKER_01]: Great ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stan Hack.
[SPEAKER_02]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_02]: Hack came a little later.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Woody English?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's been up there quite a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you know Woody very well?
[SPEAKER_02]: Just to speak to us or like, you know, I'm going to try to see him today.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's over in Newark.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He doesn't want to talk, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: He gets quite a few doubles.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it in Toledo or was it in the big leagues?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know where it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit that ball off the right field all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: He doesn't want to be interviewed very much.
[SPEAKER_01]: He doesn't?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I talked to him on the phone.
[SPEAKER_02]: I stopped by there last July, about a month or so ago to see him, and he was not in then, but I talked to his mother.
[SPEAKER_02]: His mother's living.
[SPEAKER_02]: 86-year-old, nice old lady, had a real good talk with her.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wanted to interview her after a while because she knew a lot about Woody's career.
[SPEAKER_02]: But she didn't want to be interviewed.
[SPEAKER_02]: But she did talk.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I'm going to stop over there on the way back this afternoon.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe I can sneak in.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's only 30 miles.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right on the way home, you see.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll stop in and see if I can talk.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I asked you while we were eating there if you had any problems with any players.
[SPEAKER_02]: You mentioned no problems, just a couple of fights.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was me.
[SPEAKER_01]: As far as problems, I'm not involved with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I haven't had a cold.
[SPEAKER_02]: Those stories about the fights I thought were pretty interesting.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why don't you repeat them for the tape, if you would, please.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we were playing Toronto at this time.
[SPEAKER_02]: This would be when you were back there managing the Jets?
[SPEAKER_01]: When I was managing the, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: 54, 55.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, we had a little, there wasn't always a little bit of pitching between the Toronto club and Columbus for some reason, I don't know why.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, we'd go to this ballgame and Bill Miller was pitching.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Miller?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Miller, they sent him down from the Yankees, the left handed.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we was racking him up pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: The fellas were really teeing off on him.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he began to figure, well, I guess I gotta loosen somebody up.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he threw a couple balls behind Al Pinkston's head.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, industrial.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, they were sharp, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he knocked him down both times.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Pinkston went to the bathroom, walked out to the mound, and I was coaching first base.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I ran out there to stop him, and I said, uh, we don't want to have a trouble with Al, I said let him go.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said he can't throw hard enough to break a pane of glass anyway.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nixon was a black player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Miller was a white player, a big guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: So one would pull out another, and, uh, finally, Sewell, he came out to them and said, oh, everybody was standing around the ring there, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So,
[SPEAKER_01]: Limmer called me something, I can't tell you what he called me, but I...
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the first baseman for Toronto.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I asked him, I said, are you ready?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, yeah, and I let him have it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he wasn't ready, so I knocked him down.
[SPEAKER_01]: So things come up after that, and we went to clubhouse and had a little argument, and that was all.
[SPEAKER_01]: You took care of it, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't like to talk about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, go ahead.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was 20 years younger than you, and he wasn't any small man either, was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He used to knock me down quite a bit, you know, when I played.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you're batting, you mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, hit me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Knocked me down with a ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: They tried to pitch that ball up in here, but they'd get it in the back of your head, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever walk up to the pitcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Dick Barrett.
[SPEAKER_01]: Shootin' Dick Barrett in Seattle.
[SPEAKER_01]: He knocked me down a couple of times, so I walked up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't say nothing to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just punched him in the mouth.
[SPEAKER_01]: They threw you out of the game?
Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: This fella that, uh, Fred Hutchinson, he was just breaking in then at Seattle Club.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was with us both.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the only one I can remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: This is when you were Sacramento in the 37, 38.
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Hutchinson brush you back?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Freddie Hutchinson brush you back?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he knocked me down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got hit in the head three times.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob Joyce hit me and wasn't the first to hit me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob Dutch Ruther hit me the other one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dutch Ruther?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he still around?
[SPEAKER_01]: Dutch?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's out in Colby, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not now, I don't know where he is.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was pretty old though, then, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that was right after we made that deal, in 24, when I went to...
[SPEAKER_01]: He went to the Yankees and I went to a boy school.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was getting pretty old then.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't hurt me in any way, he couldn't so much.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, Roy Parmley told me that he, in his career, he had five guys in the head.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said after each case, after he hit them, he was no good anymore.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was just wild, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was real wild.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't pitch after he... You know what he did?
[SPEAKER_01]: What the hell was hanging there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Hendricks, his manager, didn't have the ball to go at Parmer over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, Parmer, he doesn't have any guts.
[SPEAKER_01]: So Parmer goes out to pitch, you know, with the Redbirds.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the first ball he pitched, you know where he threw it?
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit the press box with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit the press box with the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, I started laughing, I said, good God, what's going to happen today?
[SPEAKER_01]: So, we went on the best and magic line there was, I just want to show Jack Hendricks that I got some guts.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit the press box, hit it in the ballpark, and it didn't happen.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know if you've ever seen it, that's a good ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I've been there once.
[SPEAKER_01]: You name it after it.
[SPEAKER_01]: You mean, when he's warm-up pitch before the game, you threw?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, the game was started, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: We hit first.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the hitter comes up and he's taking his preliminary warm-up pitches, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: Must've done himself a ball to catch me.
[SPEAKER_02]: When did Hendricks say this?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: When did Hendricks say he didn't have any guts?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's what he taught, that's what Palmer, I don't know when he did it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that's what Palmer told me, he's outscored me like that, I guess or not.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you know, every one of them hitters went up to that plate, there was ten of them, they're like, you see them?
[SPEAKER_02]: They're knee-shaking, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: They wouldn't even get near the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not even so hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's crippled now.
[SPEAKER_01]: He can get around a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's up in Monroe, Michigan.
[SPEAKER_02]: Arthritic condition, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess that's what I got too.
[SPEAKER_02]: He can get up and get around a little bit, but he was sitting at a table in the kitchen when I came in.
[SPEAKER_02]: He asked me if I wouldn't mind coming back in the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was easier for him that way.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we went and sat at a table there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Real nice.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had a real fine interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nice guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very sensitive.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was talking about John McGraw as a manager when he was with the Giants.
[SPEAKER_02]: McGraw would be real tough.
[SPEAKER_02]: with the guys that needed it.
[SPEAKER_02]: With Parmley, it didn't work that way.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used other methods.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was pretty sensitive.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very big man, but he was kind of sensitive.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know a ball player who lives down in West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll forget the word of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: His name is Kenny A.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know him?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: He pitched the first ballgame that was pitched in the Redbird Stadium.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1932, and he beat St. Paul 11-2, I think it's called.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kenny A.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he have a pretty long career?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was quite a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could go see him, man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what county he lived in.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got a directory of all ballplayers in the country.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: The addresses aren't correct.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're listed over somewhere on Broad Street, for example.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they're not up to date.
[SPEAKER_02]: But, like, Fred Blake was listed in Beckley.
[SPEAKER_02]: We went down to Beckley and there was a used car lot where he was supposed to live.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was a couple years out of date, you see.
[SPEAKER_02]: So the addresses aren't always accurate.
[SPEAKER_02]: I have a list of all those in West Virginia and I don't remember the name Ash.
[SPEAKER_01]: He lives on there somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because he's got a picture she had.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of the reunion?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's on that picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came up from under the boat.
[SPEAKER_01]: Esther, where's that picture you had we took out the ballpark at that reunion?
[SPEAKER_01]: I want to show him Cheney Atkins.
[SPEAKER_01]: He can bald eagle much better than I can.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to see him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Interview him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Find him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He knew some stories about the red bird.
[SPEAKER_00]: You mean in the group picture?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, look at all the pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, these are just old ones.
[SPEAKER_00]: We was going through all this this morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: It isn't on there.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it isn't on here.
[SPEAKER_00]: It sure is on here.
[SPEAKER_02]: There it is.
[SPEAKER_02]: Could you take a picture of us, Mrs. Bowen, just talking, if you would please?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd love to.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know who this is right here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mr. Murdock.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who wrote Parmelee?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looks just like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looks good, except he's in trouble getting around.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'll be looking at this picture together here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Look at his ass right here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, this takes a pretty good wide thing if you look so far away in here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we're not far.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're not really that far.
[SPEAKER_02]: Let's just hold it and look at it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Don't you want to look up this way?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I think we'll get a look this way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Put you on here.
[SPEAKER_00]: You might smile and see the birdie fly.
[SPEAKER_02]: Thank you very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who are all the people in there now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I don't know, but I know them all.
[SPEAKER_02]: This is the 32 Redbird team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, this is the old-timers, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's Bill Lee, Bud Farnley, Laurie McPhail, and I think that's Bluejee.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they're not identical.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Ash.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Ash here.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Carmen Hill.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Ivar Swanson?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think that's Swanny right there.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he'd be over here with Riggs.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's Lou there, Swanson.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's Louis Chauffeur, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it says this is Swanson according to the picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's do the web, English slaughter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Great picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I wish I had seen that in the paper.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You have in that pictures, are those old baseball pictures over there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Those there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they're just not civilian pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: Will you look at those?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll bring them over later.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: A lot of family pictures here, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's just his family.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: These are ones we took in 1966, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was thinking these are all baseball pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, the only old baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is all we've got.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is all I have.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the rest of these, this is him and his son in 1966 when we was in Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is he and the daughter at the same time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And these other ones are the grandchildren.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one that we kind of like.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shows you what he does most now.
[SPEAKER_02]: How big a fish was that one?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's about two pounds, that's old carp.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, what was the old ballpark?
[SPEAKER_00]: We were talking a little bit about that, O'Neill Park was it called?
[SPEAKER_00]: What was it like?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, it was a wood stadium, I mean, a wood stand and everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you see very many people there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I imagine five or six thousand.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never did see that many in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a lot of talk about some of the old ball players that played out there, like Bill Hinchman, Hank Harvey, Jack McAllister, Dummy Kim, all those, but probably go way back, I don't know, way back before I ever saw them.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got the last hit there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was the best day I had in Neal Park.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wound it up in a way to blow that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I would say, you know, I hit two doubles and two home runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was the end of the... Fourth of four.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was the end of the 30... That was in the spring of 32.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you actually play league games there that year?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: We moved from the 15th of June, we moved from Neal Park to Redbird Stadium.
[SPEAKER_02]: You got the first hit of Redbird Stadium?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: The last hit of Neo Park?
[SPEAKER_01]: And, uh, LeBorgo hit the first home run, was hitting, uh... Was, uh, Neo Park a pretty good home run park, or...?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a pretty good-sized park.
[SPEAKER_02]: How were their facilities, their showers, lockers, and things like that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Were they good?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, not too well, not too good.
[SPEAKER_01]: The pork was getting old and run down.
[SPEAKER_01]: The clubhouse was running down.
[SPEAKER_01]: The shower was leaking and everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you retired and when?
[SPEAKER_02]: For baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: What year did you retire for baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't hear you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, the last year I was at Lancaster.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I went to work for the Columbus State School over there as a tenant.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe you want this, I don't know what you do.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I was going to ask you what you did after baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I worked over there 14 years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Which school is this now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Columbus State School.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a school for mentally retarded kids like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I worked over there 14 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's where I got this bad blaze I got here.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had two boys up there, they got in a fight, and of course I was the attender, and I tried to stop them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I did stop them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had one boy sitting down in a chair, he was sitting there while I was sitting there, turned around to sit the other guy down, he'd leave the chair, and that's where I cut my leg off.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I was laying down on the floor in the office where he hit me and he wasn't going to hit me again.
[SPEAKER_01]: I grabbed him by the leg and pulled him down and I got on top of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hit him a couple times, but you're not supposed to.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're not supposed to hit him.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what I told the superintendent.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, look, I said, I didn't come over to be a punching bag for somebody.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I won't live a little while too.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, if they punch me, I'm going to punch them back.
[SPEAKER_01]: But this thing here, that's cost me a lot of money.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he's got a job.
[SPEAKER_01]: in the recreation department here, you know, after I retired.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I can't get around anymore.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did that happen?
[SPEAKER_01]: What did that happen, honey?
[SPEAKER_01]: Ten years ago?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know when it happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's been that long.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was settled in 1970, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he retired.
[SPEAKER_00]: He retired in 1970.
[SPEAKER_02]: You worked from about 56 or 57 to 70 at the State State?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was supposed to quit at 70.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, you're not supposed to work anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I went up and told him I was going to retire.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you can't retire.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, why?
[SPEAKER_01]: Why can't I retire?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you're too guy to a man.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I didn't do too good either of that, so then I did it by trying to do it better.
[SPEAKER_02]: I like that picture of you laughing like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Alright.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd like to get a picture of you two together if I may also.
[SPEAKER_02]: Alright.
[SPEAKER_02]: So was it pretty hard work over there or interesting work?
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it was interesting work.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you have any more problems like that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: They brought some kids in there and you'd go ahead and work with them and
[SPEAKER_01]: Show them how to do things and you see them progressing a little bit and it makes you feel kind of good too because you feel like you're helping them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used to take them out and play ball with them but I had to play with both teams.
[SPEAKER_01]: They wouldn't stand for me playing with one team.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, well, I played for Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they know about your baseball career?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, softball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they knew.
[SPEAKER_01]: We played softball over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they wanted to play hardball, and I brought it up at a meeting they had over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they asked me if I could get the balls and the bats.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I can get them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm not going to get them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they said, well, why?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, we haven't got the tools to play with.
[SPEAKER_01]: You haven't got a mask or breast protector, shin guards, you haven't got no bats and no gloves.
[SPEAKER_01]: And now some kids out there throwin' that hardball on, somebody's gonna get hurt.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they would've, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we didn't play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they said that we'd play softball.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's okay, so... Did you bat much?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I went out and hit really.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, hit pretty far, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I get the softball good at kids that throw it at that slow pitch, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like they...
[SPEAKER_01]: Played a game one time up in Minneapolis where they had all those home runs for the Christian Lindsey team.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were going to send the Christian Lindsey Ford team into... Christian what?
[SPEAKER_01]: Christian Lindsey Ford.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a Ford garage.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you know, they sell Ford and things like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they needed some money to go to Chicago to play in that softball tournament.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we decided that Mike Kelly said we'd go out and play them.
[SPEAKER_01]: a five inning ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm sure it's a quarter, you know, a game.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were out there and I had the devil of a crowd.
[SPEAKER_01]: A couple of them struck out five times.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now them kids throw that ball hard, you know what?
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of them do.
[SPEAKER_01]: If we wasn't playing that soft pitch, they was firing that ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever strike out five times in a regular game?
[SPEAKER_02]: I struck out four times in a ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Clyde Haddard, left-hander.
[SPEAKER_01]: Haddard.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He struck out four times.
[SPEAKER_02]: You ever hit three homers in a game?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Hit three homers in a game?
[SPEAKER_01]: Three?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I hit two home runs in one inning, twice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right here in this league, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right out here in this ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hit three one day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I hit two home runs out here in one inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I've done the same thing in Toledo.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hit two home runs in one inning.
[SPEAKER_02]: How many runs did you bat in at that inning?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was there anybody on base?
[SPEAKER_02]: Seven, one of us.
[SPEAKER_02]: Seven runs?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: One was home run to bases full, the other was two on.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a big inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that must have been quite a throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know who I hit the home run to bases for, but I don't know who the other guy was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was that one?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember the name?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's coached in baseball now, coached someplace, some university.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hey, S?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_01]: Come here, I want you to get a picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: You can just sit in the arm of the chair there.
[SPEAKER_02]: You sit in the arm of the chair, maybe?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I'm not baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: I want you.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're just good old buddies, aren't we, honey?
[SPEAKER_01]: We're good cooks.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: One other little thingy that we've had to take care of was he had some spots on his face and the surgeon at the hospital told him to see a man after he got out.
[SPEAKER_00]: So,
[SPEAKER_00]: The 4th of April, we started cobalt treatments on the face.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was one here, and here, and a big one here, and then another one right under the eye there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the one we was kind of concerned about.
[SPEAKER_00]: 20 cobalt treatments removed them all.
[SPEAKER_00]: Isn't that marvelous?
[SPEAKER_02]: They're pretty uncomfortable, I guess, aren't they?
[SPEAKER_00]: They were just skin cancers.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't hurt me at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: No feeling or anything else.
[SPEAKER_01]: The doctor asked me, he said, one of those, did it bother me any?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, no, it didn't bother me any.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, we'll take care of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we went in and made a couple of what they call blocks and put over them things and we got the other machine on us.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I took 20 of them and he said, well, the nurse, she was a hell of a baseball player, man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know why this girl is.
[SPEAKER_01]: She went to Cincinnati with her ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I could always tell whether it was that or one or all.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he took me in there and he said, well, he said, you won't have to come back for more.
[SPEAKER_01]: For how long was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: We went back, I don't know, it was three months from the last COBOL treatment.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you're fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went back here, uh, right before we went to St. Paul to see my daughter.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you should see the before and after pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was, it was just fantastic because when he first started, it was just about six weeks after the surgery, maybe not that long, maybe five or six weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he looked pretty awful.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now, he's just so great now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't look too good now, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Great.
[SPEAKER_02]: Looks like you'll have to hit 50 home runs this year.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wouldn't have been very nice, but I wish now that I had taken a picture of him the day I took him to the hospital.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wouldn't, it wouldn't have been very kind because he was just raising heck.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not knowing exactly what he was raising heck about, but he wasn't going to go.
[SPEAKER_02]: What are you worried about?
[SPEAKER_02]: About 220.5.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not much over your playing weight, was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was up, uh, 265.
[SPEAKER_01]: For a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: But when I went to the hospital, I got down to 202, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I've gained some weight since then, which I should be like, should eat like a pig all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's probably my fault.
[SPEAKER_00]: I get blamed for all that.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a good cook, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I tell you.
[SPEAKER_00]: We counted calories and we kept records and all that stuff for the longest time.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Nick would snitch on his diet.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where the trouble came in.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm here and I just got gas.
[SPEAKER_02]: The interview is over in a few minutes and I'm on my way back home.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm on my way back to get out of this gas station.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're just off the interstate.
[SPEAKER_02]: And here I go.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought I'd talk a little bit about this interview I had with Nick Cullip and with his friend, Mr. Bowen.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was a most gracious, pleasant, delightful person.
[SPEAKER_02]: They both were.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a very enjoyable interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: I arrived there about 20 after 10.
[SPEAKER_02]: A little bit late.
There we go.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's my cutoff here.
[SPEAKER_02]: There it is here.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're at 270 east.
[SPEAKER_02]: If I get on this here outer belt, then I'll get talking.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm going off on it now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Rides are about 20 after 10 at their apartment.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a vague apartment housing complex, a whole series of apartments over a number of blocks there.
[SPEAKER_02]: A not very
[SPEAKER_02]: tightly kept neighborhood, but probably lower middle class, I suppose you'd call it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And there were some newspapers laying in the parking lot behind, or the series of apartments where I parked.
[SPEAKER_02]: And there were a few cats and unkempt kids.
[SPEAKER_02]: but the apartment itself in which the Nick Pollock lives and with Mrs. Bowen I guess it's her apartment he's staying with her is uh was neat it was a little congested it's very big they have the living room and they have the a kitchenette a bedroom and a bathroom there none of them very big
[SPEAKER_02]: And the dining area is a little table just off the living room and off the kitchenette.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I got there about 20 after 10.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just left about 1.30.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was there over three hours.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they invited me very warmly to stay for lunch, and I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we had the tape run about 10.30 maybe, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: 12-15, then shut it off while we ate.
[SPEAKER_02]: About a half an hour, then put it back on again afterwards.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kept on going until about 1-30.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I have one full tape, 90 minutes.
[SPEAKER_02]: I have this second tape where you guys got going on the first side of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Got two-thirds right through and I'm finishing that up now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay, Nick Collip is
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a big, heavy sick man.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not a big stomach.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looked good.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looked pretty tripped.
[SPEAKER_02]: No hair, he said, of course.
[SPEAKER_02]: A big face, round, jovial face.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was in good humor.
[SPEAKER_02]: He recalled things well.
[SPEAKER_02]: He spoke pretty well.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a little hearing problem, so a couple of questions I had to repeat.
[SPEAKER_02]: And a couple of minor points he didn't get that I was trying to make.
[SPEAKER_02]: He has a bad leg, which as he tells in the tape there, I think Kurt, when he was an attendant at the boys' industrial school, or the boys' school for, state school for retarded kids, I guess, vocational school or something, he was trying to break up a fight, one of the kids hit him in the leg with a chair.
[SPEAKER_02]: And this, he showed me the leg, it's all bent in different directions, left knee,
[SPEAKER_02]: and this has caused him trouble from time to time.
[SPEAKER_02]: He does walk with a limp.
[SPEAKER_02]: During the lunch hour it came out that he had very serious surgery last January.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a complication from a prostate gland problem, which uremic poisoning had set in.
[SPEAKER_02]: They finally got him to the doctor.
[SPEAKER_02]: life and death for a while there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Finally they drained her.